Charles M. Kurtz
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1843-1940, undated, Series 2:
  Sketch of arrangement of pictures for exhibition by Henry Ward Ranger in letter to Charles M. Kurtz from Ranger, December 8, 1891: AAA 4811 (381)
  Sketch of holder for Christmas candles by Charles M. Kurtz, December 16, 1891: AAA 4811 (429)
  Print (?) as invitation for exhibition of work by J.H. Dolph and Hamilton Hamilton, January, 1892: AAA 4811 (614)
  Child's watercolor drawings by Elizabeth Kurtz, February 4, 1892: AAA 4811 (743-745)
  Child's drawings by Elizabeth Kurtz, May 12, 1892: AAA 4811 (1195-6)
  Sketch illustrating decorations worn on official European uniforms at dinner for 1893 Fair, May 5, 1893: AAA 4812 (1306),
  Thumb nail sketch of painting by Will H. Low, "a female tying the Sandals of Love" by Charles Ward Rhodes, June 19, 1893: AAA 4812 (1453)
  Sketch of proposed picture frame by Charles Ward Rhodes, August 23, 1893: AAA 4813 (205)
  Installation diagram of St. Louis Exposition [annual regional fair] by Charles Ward Rhodes, Sept. 8, 1893: AAA 4813 (247-248)
  Sketch of painting by Gagneau by Charles Ward Rhodes, exhibited at the St. Louis Exposition, October 5, 1893: AAA 4813 (308)
  Sketch of Charles M. Kurtz's college fraternity pin, February 2, 1894: AAA 4813, (623)
  Diagram of arrangement of seating for table on board ship by Charles M. Kurtz, March 10, 1894: AAA 4813 (738)
  Diagram of boats on sea and pig-skin water cask by Charles M. Kurtz, March 18, 1894: AAA 4813 (818)
  Diagram of gallery for St. Louis Exposiion by Charles Ward Rhodes, April 27, 1894: AAA 4813 (938)
  Floor plan of vestibule exhibition area of St. Louis Museum by Charles Ward Rhodes, May 17, 1894: AAA 4813 (1022)
  Floor plan of galleries for St. Louis exhibition with measurements by Charles Ward Rhodes, August 13, 1894: AAA 4813 1246
  Thumbnail sketch of beer drinker by Botto, October 1, 1894: AAA 4814 (5)
  Sketch of fur wrap by Charles M. Kurtz, June, 16, 1895: AAA 4814 (574)
  Diagram for hanging America pictures at St. Louis Exposition, 1899 by Charles Ward Rhodes: AAA 4816 (901)
  Floor plan by Charles Ward Rhodes for Second Annual Exhibition of the Architectural Club of St. Louis, April 11, 1900: AAA 4816 (1152)
  Floor plan and elevation sketch by Halsey C. Ives of his country house: AAA 4816 (1354-55)
  Thumbnail sketch of sailboat at sea by Frederick E. Bartlett, January 23, 1901: AAA 4817 (36)
  Valentine from Julia Wilder Kurtz to Charles M. Kurtz, February 13, 1902: AAA 4817 (619)
  Illustrated letter: sketch of toddler [Isabella S. Kurtz] by Julia Wilder Kurtz, March 3, 1902: AAA 4817 (661)
  Thank you note from Julia Wilder Kurtz to Charles M. Kurtz illustrated with ink drawing of bunny, February 16, 1902: AAA 4817 (1076)
  Self-portrait caricature as signature by Charles M. Kurtz June 10, 1903, June 15, 1903, June 16, 1903: AAA 4817 (1208), (1217), (1221)
  Self-portrait caricature with hat as signature by Charles M. Kurtz, June 28, 1903: AAA 4817 (1237)
  Self-portrait caricature as signature by Charles M. Kurtz November 14, 1903: AAA 4817 (1307)
  Sketch of retriever dog by Dudlee, Dec. 19, 1904: AAA 4818 (182)
  Sketch of Bulgarian Order of Merit Cross awarded to Charles M. Kurtz by himself enclosed in March 3, 1905 letter: AAA 4818 (305)
  - Undated letters, unidentified writers (Reel 4804, Frame 75-92)
  - Partially dated letters, identified by first names (Reel 4804, Frame 93-136)
  - Undated letters, identified by first names mainly to Julia from Nina [Starkweather?] (Reel 4804, Frame 137-183)
  - Correspondence, A, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 184-215)
    (mainly from Letty H. Alexander, also S.P. Avery)
  - Correspondence, B-C, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 216-296)
    (J. Jay Barber, Fred E. Bartlett, Geo. F. Brownell, Geo. H. Bogert, W. Gedney Bunce, Howard Russell Butler, F.S. Church)
  - Correspondence, D-E, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 297-327)
    (Louis P. Dessar, Thos. W. Dewing, Walter McEwen)
  - Correspondence, F-G, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 328-377)
    (Ben Foster, Sara Hallowell, D. F. Hasbrouck, Childe Hassam, Albert Herter, Alfred C. Howland, Henry S. Hubbell)
  - Correspondence, I, J, K, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 378-395)
    (Halsey C. Ives, Hugh Bolton Jones, Ed. G. Kennedy, Chas. M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, Kurtz, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 396-461)
    (Kurtz family and some "L" correspondents)
  - Correspondence, M, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 462-506)
    (Macaulay Stevenson, Cornelia F. Maury, Jervis McEntee, Gari Melchers, Wm. Morgan, H. Mowbray, Hermann Dudley Murphy, [E.?] Muybridge)
  - Correspondence, N, O, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 507-521)
    (Theodore C. Noé, Ogden [Wood?])
  - Correspondence, P, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 522-532)
    (David C. Preyer)
  - Correspondence, R, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 533-565)
    (F.K.M. Rehn, Robert Reid, Chas. Ward Rhodes)
  - Correspondence, Sa-Sm, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 566-596)
    (Augusta St. Gaudens, Semple family, F. Hopkinson Smith)
  - Correspondence, Sn-Sz, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 597-641)
    (Otto Stark, Starkweather family, Edward J. Steichen, Jean Stevenson [Mrs. Macauley Stevenson], Stephenson family)
  - Correspondence, T-V, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 642-659)
    (Grosvenor Thomas, Patty Thum)
  - Correspondence, Wa, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 660-685)
    ([Henry] Watrous)
  - Correspondence, We-Z, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 686-713)
    (Lyman H. Weeks, Irving B. Wiles, Wallace Wood, G.J. Zolnay)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1848-1869 (Reel 4804, Frame 717-740)
    (arranged chronologically, Kurtz family)
  - Correspondence, 1870-1879 (Reel 4804, Frame 741-775)
    (Kurtz family)
  - Correspondence, 1883[?] (Reel 4804, Frame 776-795)
    (Kurtz family, A. D. Smith)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-Dec. 1880 (Reel 4804, Frame 796-834)
  - Correspondence, 1881, undated (Reel 4804, Frame 835-870)
    (many notes from artists explaining the iconography etc. of their pictures for representation in Academy Notes, Harry Chase, Henry Farrar, George Fuller, R. S. Gifford, T. Hovenden, F.K.M. Rehn, H.W. Robbins, J. H. Witt)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1-5, (sic) [Feb. 1-March 10 1881] (Reel 4804, Frame 871-965)
    (J.F Cropsey, Jervis McEntee, F. A. Silva, Wm. Sartain, Geo. B. Wood, J. Carroll Beckwith, Thomas Eakins, Geo C. Lambdin, Worthington Whittredge, J.G. Brown, James C. Beckwith, Thomas Moran, F. A. Bridgman, F. D. Millet)
  - Correspondence, March 11-31 (sic) [March 11-April 5], 1881 (Reel 4804, Frame 966-992)
    (Geo. C. Lambdin, Rosina Emmet, S. R. Koehler, W. Whittredge, J. F. Cropsey)
  - Correspondence, April 1-30, 1881 (Reel 4804, Frame 993-1017)
    (Stephen Parrish, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, May-Dec., 1881 (Reel 4804, Frame 1018-1041)
    (Eastman Johnson, Starkweather family)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-Dec., 1882 (Reel 4804, Frame 1042-1072)
    (Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-April, 1883 (Reel 4804, Frame 1073-1100)
    (Rosina Emmet, Jervis McEntee, F. A. Bridgman, Charles Sprague Pearce, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, May-July, (sic) [May-Aug. 8], 1883 (Reel 4804, Frame 1101-1125)
    (William Sartain, L.B. di Cesnola, Kurtz family, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, Aug.-Sept., 1883 (Reel 4804, Frame 1126-1194)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Geo. I. Seney, Jervis McEntee, Ed. H. Blashfield, Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, Nov.1883 (Reel 4804, Frame 1195-1236)
    (Julia Stephenson, Charles M. Kurtz, telegrams from artists authorizing sales of their pictures at Louisville Exposition)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1883 (Reel 4804, Frame 1237-1336)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, James D. Smillie, Julia Stephenson, Thomas B. Clarke, A. Parton)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1884 (Reel 4804, Frame 1332-1404)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1884 (Reel 4804, Frame 1400-1421)
    (Julia Stephenson, The Tribune, Washington & Jefferson College)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1884 (Reel 4804, Frame 1422-1451)
    (Clara McChesney, J. Jay Barber, Chas. Lanman)
  - Correspondence, April, 1884 (Reel 4804, Frame 1452-1523)
    (J. Jay Barber, Julia Stephenson, Charles M. Kurtz, D. Huntington)
  - Correspondence, May 11-15, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 1-16)
    (Frank Waller, F. K. M. Rehn, A.T. Bricher, A.P. Ryder, Carleton Wiggans)
  - Correspondence, May 16-20, 1884 (sic) [May 16-31, 1884] (Reel 4805, Frame 16-87)
    (A.T.Bricher, Jervis McEntee, Arthur Parton)
  - Correspondence, June 1-5, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 88-103)
    (A.H. Wyant)
  - Correspondence, June 6-10, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 104-127)
    (Percival DeLuce, Frank Waller, Wm. L. Sonntag, W.S. Macy, Arthur Parton, Thomas B. Clarke)
  - Correspondence, June 10-15, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 128-146)
    (Thos. Hovenden)
  - Correspondence, June 16-20, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 147-181)
    (Herter Brothers)
  - Correspondence, June 21-30, 1884 (sic) [June 21-July 10,1884] (Reel 4805, Frame 182-275)
    (Thomas B. Clarke, Bruce Crane, Julia Stephenson, A.T. Bricher, S. R. Koehler, D. Huntington)
  - Correspondence, July 11-15, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 276-303)
    (Eastman Johnson, A.T. Bricher, H. Bolton Jones)
  - Correspondence, July 16-20, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 304-328)
    (Wm. T. Richards, Thomas B. Clarke, T. Moran, L.E. Wilmarth, Julia Stephenson, Eastman Johnson)
  - Correspondence, July 21-25 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 329-356)
    (Bertha von Hillern, Maria J. C. Becket, E. L. Henry)
  - Correspondence, July 26-31, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 357-374)
    (Wm. T. Richards)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1-5, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 375-404)
    (A. D. Vorce & Co. Fine Arts, Jasper F. Cropsey)
  - Correspondence, August 6-15, 1884 (sic) [August 6-31, 1884] (Reel 4805, Frame 405-472)
    (Charles Warren Eaton, E. Wood Perry, Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, September 1-10, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 473-501)
    (E. Wood Perry, Julia Stephenson, Bertha von Hillern, S. R. Koehler)
  - Correspondence, September 11-20, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 502-533)
    (Julia Stephenson, Edward Gay)
  - Correspondence, September 21-30, 1884 (sic) [September 21-October 10, 1884] (Reel 4805, Frame 534-605)
    (Francis A. Silva, E. Wood Perry, Julia Stephenson, Thomas B. Clark)
  - Correspondence, October 11-15, 1884 (sic), [October 11-22, 1884] (Reel 4805, Frame 606-752)
    (Julia Stephenson, Arthur Parton, Patty Thum, F.A. Silva, Thomas B. Clarke, A.T.Bricher)
  - Correspondence, October 23-25, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 753-790)
    (D. B. Kurtz, Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, October 26-28, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 791-835)
    (Julia Stephenson, S. R. Koehler)
  - Correspondence, October 28-31, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 836-875)
    (Julia Stephenson, J.Jay Barber)
  - Correspondence, November 1-2, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 876-900)
    (Julia Stephenson, J. Jay Barber)
  - Correspondence, November 3-5, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 901-930)
    (Julia Stephenson, Thomas B. Clarke)
  - Correspondence, November 6-16, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 931-952)
    (Julia Stephenson, Geo. Pullman, E. Wood Perry)
  - Correspondence, November 11-15, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 953-1012)
    (Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, November 16-17, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 1013-1037)
  - Correspondence, November 21-23, 1884 (sic) [November 21-December 22, 1884] (Reel 4805, Frame 1038-1072)
    (F. E. Bartlett, Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, December 21-25, 1884 (Reel 4805, Frame 1073-1423)
  - Correspondence, December 26-28, 1884 (sic) [December 26-December 31, 1884] (Reel 4805, Frame 1424-1485)
  - Correspondence, 1885, undated (Reel 4806, Frame 1-25)
    (William Morgan, E. Wood Perry, Alf Trumble)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1-5, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 26-78)
    (Julia Stephenson, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 6-10, 1885 (sic) [Jan. 6-14] 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 79-150)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Julia Stephenson, Wm. Semple)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 16-20, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 151-186)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 21-31, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 187-242)
    (Julia Stephenson, Alf. Trumble, Wm. Semple, Geo. McKinstry, Frederick J. Waugh)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1-10, (sic) [Feb. 1-28] 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 243-339)
    (Julia Stephenson, Charles M. Kurtz, Starkweather family, Bruce Crane, Walter Shirlaw, Patty Thum)
  - Correspondence, March 1-5, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 366-391)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Julia Stephenson, G. H. McCord)
  - Correspondence, March 6-15, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 340-365)
    (Julia Stephenson, Wm. Semple, Charles M. Kurtz, Frederick Keppel)
  - Correspondence, March 16-31, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 392-424)
    (Julia Stephenson, Andrew Cowan, Harper & Brothers, Washington & Jefferson College)
  - Correspondence, April 1-10, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 425-470)
  - Correspondence, April 11-20, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 471-492)
    (Wm. Henry Goodyear-Metropolitan Museum, Edwin Linton -Washington & Jefferson College, Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, April 21-30, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 493-522)
    (Wm. Semple, Charles M. Kurtz, James. D. Smillie, Wm. Semple, Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, May 1-10, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 523-550)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Wm. Henry Goodyear Metropolitan Museum -L.P.DiCesnola, Julia Stephenson, Patty Thum, Wm. Semple, James D. Smillie)
  - Correspondence, May 11-20, (sic) [May 11-31, 1885] (Reel 4806, Frame 551-616)
    (James D. Smillie, Charles M. Kurtz, Wm. Semple, Otto H. Bacher, Percy Moran, Julia Stephenson, J. C. Nicoll, Alf. Trumbull, Geo. Wharton Edwards)
  - Correspondence, June 1-20, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 617-644)
    (James D. Smillie, Charles Melville Dewey, Julia Stephenson, Metropolitan Museum-W. Forman, Charles M. Kurtz, Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, June 21-30, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 645-682)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Julia Stephenson, Wm. Semple, Cecilia Beaux, J. & R. Lamb, Patty Thum, S. R. Koehler)
  - Correspondence, July 1-5, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 683-702)
    (Wm. Semple, Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, July 6-10, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 703-740)
    (W. C. Bauer, Geo. C. Lambdin, Alf Trumble, Charles M. Kurtz, Wm. Semple, A. Parton, W. Whittredge, Edward Moran, Bruce Crane, Patty Thum)
  - Correspondence, July 11-20, (sic) [July 11-27, 1885] (Reel 4806, Frame 741-787)
    (James D. Smillie, Charles M. Kurtz, E. H. Blashfield, Max Weyl, J. Alden Weir)
  - Correspondence, July 26-30, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 788-811)
    (Julia Stephenson, Charles M. Kurtz, E. H. Blashfield, Starkweather family, Alf. Trumble, J. Jay Barber)
  - Correspondence, August 1-5, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 812-829)
  - Correspondence, August 1-10, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 830-859)
    (Julia Stephenson, Charles M. Kurtz, Metropolitan Museum of Art (Wm. Henry Goodyear), S. R. Koehler)
  - Correspondence, August 11-15, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 860-876)
    (Julia Stephenson, United States Indian Service (Geo. A. McKinstry)
  - Correspondence, August 16-20, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 877-906)
    (Julia Stephenson, Charles M. Kurtz, J. H. Dolph)
  - Correspondence, August 20-24, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 907-936)
  - Correspondence, August 25-31, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 937-961)
    (Julia Stephenson, J. Francis Murphy, Alf. Trumble, Mrs. J. F. Cropsey, Nina Batchelor, Patty Thum, Alf. Trumble)
  - Correspondence, September 1-3, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 962-991)
    (Henry Mosler, Julia Stephenson, Charles M. Kurtz, Harry Chase)
  - Correspondence, September 4-5, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 992-1020)
    (Alfred Fredericks, Charles M. Kurtz, Julia Stephenson, J. H. Dolph)
  - Correspondence, September 6-8, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 1021-1056)
    (Wm. Bliss Baker, Charles M. Kurtz, Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, September 9-10, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 1057-1087)
    (Julia Stephenson, E. Wood Perry, J. Jay Barber)
  - Correspondence, September 11-12, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 1088-1105)
    (F.K.M. Rehn, Julia Stephenson, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, September 13-14, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 1106-1125)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, American Art Association-Thomas Ellis Kirby, Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, September 15-17, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 1126-1146)
    (Alfred Trumble, Alfred Fredericks, Charles M. Kurtz, Julia Stephenson)
  - Correspondence, September 18-20 (sic) [September 18-25, 1885] (Reel 4806, Frame 1147-1235)
    (Metropolitan Museum of Art-Wm. Henry Goodyear, Julia Stephenson, Charles M. Kurtz, Wm. Morgan, Starkweather family, Geo. A. McKinstry)
  - Correspondence, September 26-30 (sic) [September 26- October 6,1885] (Reel 4806, Frame 1236-1306)
    (J. B. Bristol, Julia Stephenson, Charles M. Kurtz, E. Wood Perry, W. R. Forman, E. H. Blashfield, Charles Melville Dewey, J. Francis Murphy, J. H. Dolph, American Art Association)
  - Correspondence, October 11-20, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 1307-1332)
    (American Art Association-K. Timpson, D. B. Kurtz, J. Jay Barber, J. H. Dolph, E. Wood Perry, Thos. Ellis Kirby, J. B. Bristol, Mrs. J. F. Cropsey)
  - Correspondence, October 21-31, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 1333-1359)
    (Mrs. J. F. Cropsey, American Art Association-K. Timpson, E. Wood Perry, C. Harry Eaton, Francis Hopkinson Smith, Alfred Kappes, John A. Elder, Harry Chase)
  - Correspondence, November 1-15, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 1360-1382)
    (Julia Stephenson Kurtz, J. B. Bristol, M. F.H.DeHaas, Wm. Semple, S. R. Koehler, D. B. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, November 16-30, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 1383-1415)
    (Carlton T. Chapman, American Art Association-Katharine Timpson, Patty Thum, D. W. Tryon, F.A. Silva, Wm. Semple, Henry A. Ferguson, Charles Melville Dewey, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, December 1-15, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 1416-1454)
    (Patty Thum, Henry A. Ferguson, F. K. M. Rehn, J. Francis Murphy, Wm. Semple, American Art Association-Katharine Timpson)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 16-31, 1885 (Reel 4806, Frame 1455-1477)
    (William Semple, National Academy of Design-T. Addison Richards, George Wharton Edwards, Jennie Brownscombe, Charles M. Kurtz, D. B. Kurtz)
  - Undated Correspondence (Reel 4807, Frame 2-10)
    (Alice Barber, Elliott Daingerfield, F. S. Lamb)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1-12, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 11-48)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, American Art Association-Katharine Timpson and Thos. E. Kirby, Patty Thum)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 17-29, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 49-68)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Patty Thum, Wm. Semple)
  - Correspondence, February 1-12, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 69-111)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Julia Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, February 13-16, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 112-153)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, D. B. Kurtz, Wm. Semple)
  - Correspondence, February 17-26, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 154-165)
    (Louis Richard, J. N. Marble, Wm. R. Warner & Bro., Medals & Badges)
  - Correspondence, March 6-31, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 166-209)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, D. B. Kurtz, Wm. Semple, Southern Exposition Company-J. M. Wright)
  - Correspondence, April 1-15, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 210-248)
    (Wm. Semple, Charles M. Kurtz, Carl Brenner, Southern Exposition (J. M. Wright)
  - Correspondence, April 15-30, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 249-283)
    (Herbert A. Levy, L. M. Wiles, F.K.M.Rehn, D.B. Kurtz, Wm. Semple, T.W. Wood, R. E. Brown, F.S. Church, C.M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, May 1-22, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 284-319)
    (Wm. Semple, Southern Exposition at Louisville-Maj. Wright)
  - Correspondence, May 24-30, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 320-359)
    (L. S. Silva, Wm. Semple, Kurtz family, Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts-Geo. Corliss, G. W. Conant, D. B. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, June 1-8, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 360-376)
    (Wm. Semple, Cassell & Co., Ltd, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, June 9-10, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 377-395)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, William Semple, S. R. Koehler)
  - Correspondence, June 11-14, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 396-427)
    (William Semple, Charles M. Kurtz, Louis Kurtz, F. S. Church, Julia S. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, June 15-16, (sic) [June 15-17] 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 428-450)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, William Semple, Julia S. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, June 19-23, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 451-489)
    (Julia S. Kurtz, Irving R. Wiles, Charles M. Kurtz, William Semple)
  - Correspondence, June 22-28, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 490-522)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, William Semple)
  - Correspondence, June 29-July 5, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 523-559)
    (Julia S. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, Kurtz family, William Semple)
  - Correspondence, July 6-10, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 560-581)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, D. B. Kurtz, Mary E. Williams)
  - Correspondence, July 11-14, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 582-613)
    (Julia S. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, D. B. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, July 15-20, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 614-656)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Elizabeth Coffin, Julia S. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, July 21-27, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 657-692)
    (P. Thum, Julia S. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, J. F. Weir)
  - Correspondence, July 28-31, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 693-720)
    (E. L. Henry, D.B. Kurtz, Wm. Semple, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, August 1-6, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 721-769)
    (Julia S. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, D.B. Kurtz, William Semple)
  - Correspondence, August 7-9, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 770-809)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, American Art Association-Katharine Timpson, Julia S. Kurtz, D.B. Kurtz, A. H. Wyant)
  - Correspondence, August 10-21, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 808-834)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Frederick J. Waugh, Julia S. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, August 22-25 [August 22-Sept. 7], 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 835-902)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, D.B. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, Alice Barber, Wm. St. J. Harper, Mary E. Williams, Thos. A. Wilmurt, D.F. Hasbrouck, Wm. Semple)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 10-11, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 903-927)
    (Julia S. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, W. M. Brown, T. Addison Richards, D. B. Kurtz, S. R. Koehler)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 12-17, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 928-966)
    (Jervis McEntee, Charles M. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, Edward Moran, [Jean Leon] Gerome Ferris)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 20-24, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 967-992)
    (D.B. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, S.R. Koehler)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 25-30, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 993-1028)
    (Julia S. Kurtz, Emil Carlsen, Edward Gay, S.P. Avery, A. A. Willits)
  - Correspondence, October 2-7, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 1029-1063)
    (H.E. Brown, D.B. Kurtz, S.R. Koehler, Julia S. Kurtz, D.F. Hasbrouck)
  - Correspondence, October 8-15, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 1064-1104)
    (J.H. Dolph, Frederick W. Freer, Charles M. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, Herbert A. Levy, Wm. Morgan)
  - Correspondence, October 16-24, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 1105-1132)
    (Julia S. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, D. F. Hasbrouck, Wm. Morgan, Thos. P. Anshutz, Mary Kollock)
  - Correspondence, October 25-31, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 1133-1172)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, D. F. Hasbrouck, Halsey C. Ives, Irving R. Wiles, Julia S. Kurtz,Henry R. Poore, Thomas P. Anshutz, George H. Smillie, S. P. Avery, J.B. Bristol)
  - Correspondence, November 1-11, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 1173-1231)
    (E.Wood Perry, Jr., Charles M. Kurtz, Geo. H. Clements, D.B. Kurtz, D. F. Hasbrouck, Wm. H. Lippincott, J. S. Kurtz, James D. Smillie)
  - Correspondence, November 13-22, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 1232-1271)
    (L.P. di Cesnola, Edward Moran, Charles M. Kurtz, E. Wood Perry, Wm. H. Lippincott, D. Huntington, Doll & Richards, Joseph Lauber, Alf. Trumble, H. W. Ranger)
  - Correspondence, November 23-30, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 1272-1302)
    (William Semple, D.B. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz
  - Correspondence, December 2-13, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 1303-1325)
  - Correspondence, December 14-29, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 1326-1344)
    (Earle's Galleries, W.T. Walters)
  - Correspondence, January 1-10, 1887 (Reel 4807, Frame 1345-1374)
    (Wm. Semple, D.B. Kurtz, J. Francis Murphy, Stephenson family